Jan Jerling

6 March 1995 | Cape Town, South Africa

+27 84 910 1007

jan.jerling@gmail.com
www.linkedin.com/in/jan-jerling

Profile

With more than half a decade of experience in the Tech industry - serving as a solutions consultant to international conglomerates, as a Principal in software implementation and as the primary data expert on user behaviour for the leading online retailer in South Africa - I am the prime candidate for any organisation searching for a capable employee. Problem solving and efficiency are my key drivers. I believe that working together to improve and automate systems and processes through the use of technology and data, while always being cognizant of the human, is the foundation of any successful undertaking. I am a proponent of honesty and communication in the workplace, I thrive in team environments and also have no problem with self-motivation or solo work. Regardless of role or company, I have managed to consistently exceed expectations resulting in positive impacts for the involved businesses and people.

Professional Experience

Takealot.com Business Intelligence Analyst

Cape Town Aug 2022-present

As the sole Product BI Analyst, I:

- Mastered the concepts surrounding Big Data as it pertains to user tracking events.
- Designed and built data pipelines that efficiently and automatically aggregate every user interaction into usable data marts.
- Designed and built comprehensible and valuable reports that translate billions of user interactions into high-level insights which lead to actionable requirements that improve the product and the company's profitability.
- Collaborated on the design of new feature tests to improve the product and promote desirable user interaction.

Inovo Telecoms Principal Application Engineer

Durbanville Jan 2022-Aug 2022

• Lead and collaborated on the design and specifications for the Woolworths Financial Services call centre workflow user interface. The project was in rescue mode before my arrival. I was tasked to define the requirements and timeframe for a minimum viable product. Subsequently the client retracted their cancellation threat and the project has continued successfully since.

Johannesburg Aug 2018-Nov 2021

- Designed demand management systems for retail corporations in the EMEA and APAC regions including Super Retail Group, Page Industries, Pepkor and Ultra Liquors; to increase profit and reduce overstock and under-stock levels.
- Successfully implemented the above designs from post design stage to go-live stage drastically reducing and optimising user workload and providing substantial ROI for the client.
- Effectively managed and completed all the above mentioned projects with all stakeholders satisfied.

Education

Stellenbosch University | 2014-2017

Bachelor of Engineering in Industrial Engineering (Completed in minimum possible time)

 Thesis: "A multi-objective approach towards designing a decision support tool for group assignment" (84%). Tool built in R using a simulated annealing mathematical model.

Uplands College | 2009-2013

Matriculation (NSC) - 85%

5-year consecutive Top 5 academic achiever in my year group. Mathematics (84%); Probability, Data Handling & Geometry (87%); Physical Sciences (83%); Engineering Drawing & Design (91%).

Tech Exposure

GCP	•••○	R	•••○	DevExpress	••○○
GBQ	••••	Python	•000	Javascript	•000
SQL	••••	Tableau	••○○	Firebase	•••○
Looker	••••	С	••○○		

Other Achievements

- House Committee (HK) 2 consecutive years at Simonsberg Residence.
- All-rounder of the year for excellence in Academics, Sports, Culture & Service Simonsberg Residence.
- Best 4th Year Academic Simonsberg Residence.
- End of Year Speaker one of 3 chosen students from Stellenbosch Industrial Engineering.
- Head Boy Uplands College.
- Head of Boarding & Senate Uplands College.
- Founders Award for outstanding achievement in all facets of school life Uplands College.
- Honours Rugby and Academics at Uplands College.
- 1st Team Captain for Hockey & Soccer Uplands College.
- Headmaster's Award for consistent excellence in all aspects of school life Uplands College.
- Head of House Uplands Preparatory School.
- Frequent Bulletjie Rugby try scorer Pre-primary.